# 烤鸡翅 皮脆汁又多
Roasted chicken wings, crispy skin and juicy meat
# 这是什么好东西
What delicacy is this?
# 这个您一直跟我说 说咱家鸡翅好吃
Well, you’ve been telling me that our chicken wings are very tasty
# 实际上这个鸡翅很简单的
Actually this is a really simple recipe
# 待会我一教大家就会了
You guys can learn this immediately after I teach you later on
# 一边说一边干活 别白话
Work as you chat along, don’t just waste time talking
# 咱们挑选这种整翅
We have to choose chicken wings like this, a complete one
# 这个要经过泡水 还有出血
We have to soak this in water and remove the excess blood inside the wings
# 就是挤出翅膀上血管里边的血
Which is by squeezing the blood in the blood vessels inside
# 你看我给大家操作一下
Look, I can demonstrate it to you
# 这里边有一根血管
There is a blood vessel inside here
# 捋着这根血管 把这血给它挤出来
Hold it and squeeze out the blood inside
# 看到了么 这个咱们已经挤过一次了
Look, we have already squeezed this once
# 现在清洗得非常干净了 小窍门来了
We cleaned it thoroughly, here comes the little tip!
# 这鸡翅要泡够时间
You must soak the chicken wings for a time long enough
# 换三次水 两个小时换一次水
Change the water for 3 times and change it every 2 hours
# 夏天是一个小时换一次水
Change it once an hour during summer
# 然后每次水都要把它
Remember to squeeze out the blood
# 血管里的血往给它外撸一撸
when you change the water
# 因为我们这么多年
Because for so many years
# 这个鸡翅是一道非常受欢迎的菜
The chicken wings have been a very popular dish
# 三叔跟我说了好几次要让我做这鸡翅
San Shu asked me quite a few times to cook the dish
# 给我下了命令了
He gave me an order
# 让我必须把这鸡翅教给大家
That I must teach you guys about this recipe
# 好 鸡翅都已经洗的很干净了
Okay, the chicken wings are clean now
# 洗干净之后放在这儿
Put it aside when you are done cleaning them
# 咱们切一点洋葱
Let’s slice some onions
# 我每次切都是让它顶刀切
I slice onions with the flat side down every time
# 因为它这样释放洋葱的味道好
To release the aroma better
# 然后我再教大家调一个料
Next I would like to teach you making a marinade
# 把这孜然炒好 放进去
Toast some cumin seeds and put it into the blender
# 这生孜然搁到锅里边干焙一下
Toast the cumin seeds in a wok or a pan
# 焙出香味来就可以了
until it is aromatic and that’s done
# 然后放一点五香粉 这五香粉的量
Then, some five-spices powder
# 一定不要把孜然的味儿盖住
The five-spices must not overpower the aroma of the cumin
# 黑胡椒也是跟五香粉一样
Same goes with the black pepper
# 好 够了
Okay, that’s enough
# 这儿有白胡椒吧 再搁一点
You have some white pepper powder right? Let’s put some of that
# 好
Yeah
# 接下来呢就是放盐
Then, put some salt
# 五个鸡翅 一勺 两勺
5 chicken wings, let’s put 2 spoons of salt
# 这次我教大家腌的是干腌
This time I am teaching you guys to make a dry rub
# 我店里边用的都是水淹
Normally we use wet rub in my restaurant
# 来吧 齐活儿
Okay done
# 黑胡椒的味道太好了
The fragrant of the black pepper is awesome!
# 这个胡椒打完了以后你闻闻香不香
Can you smell the aroma？
# 真香啊
Nice!
# 给它往里边一撒
Pour it inside together with the onions
# 拌匀 要是干的话可以适当的放点水
Mix well, if you think it’s too dry you can add some water
# 我觉得还是水淹的比较好
I still prefer a wet rub
# 因为水淹的入味比较快
Because the flavour can penetrate more easily
# 咱还是放一点水把
Let’s put some water into the marinade
# 要使劲攥一攥 把洋葱的味道给它攥出来
You have to rub it with strength to release the flavour of the onions
# 给它碰撞出来
Release all the flavours!
# 看看 这样就腌好了
Look, we are done with the marinating
# 假如咱们家里边要是有条件的话呢
If you have other seasoning ingredients at your house,
# 0:02:32.380, 0:02:37.040
# 您可以放一点蚝油
# You can out some oyster sauce
# 但是我是不建议放 就是要它的原味
But I don’t recommend it, I prefer the original flavour
# 好 这样给它腌上三个小时
Okay, marinate it for 3 hours
# 烤箱调到二百二十度就可以烤了
Preheat the oven to 220°C
# 就最高火吧
Let’s set it at the highest temperature
# 但是我为了争取时间
To save some time,
# 我把提前腌好的几个咱先烤上
I’ve marinated some chicken wings beforehand and we can roast them now
# 你看这个鸡翅腌完了之后是这样
This is how the wings look like after marinating
# 看出来了吧 光滑 亮
Can you see that? Smooth and glossy
# 这个就是把这个料再腌好之后
To achieve that, rinse the chicken wings
# 给它用水冲一下
after marinating
# 冲一下之后把上边料渣冲下去
Rinse off the residue of the marinade
# 现在就开烤了 上烤盘
Let’s start roasting, take out the tray now
# 烤盘就不用刷油了
We don’t need to grease the tray in advance
# 因为这个鸡翅它本身会出油
Because there is fat in the chicken wings
# 网友们 这鸡翅其实真是简单
Friends, this dish is truly simple
# 这鸡翅吃的是原味的香
We can enjoy the original chicken flavour
# 二百三 咱们烤多长时间啊老冯
230°C, how long should we roast it, Uncle Feng?
# 这个我们在店里一般都是在半个小时
Well, it takes around half an hour in our restaurant
# 咱们这烤箱咱们看吧 观察着来吧
But this is a different oven, let’s observe it and decide later on
# 因为它要求表面要金黄
Because the chicken wings need to develop a golden crust
# 然后皮脆肉嫩
And the skin has to be crispy with a tender inside
# 咱们就等着了
Just wait
# 鸡翅到点儿啦 闻着味儿怎么样
It's time. How does it smell?
# 看看 这是老冯烤鸡翅
Look at this, Feng’s roasted chicken wings
# 三叔给出盘儿了
San Shu is serving the dish
# 真不错 拿出来味儿就出来了
Such a wonderful dish, you can smell the aroma once it’s been taken out
# 网友们 了不得了啊 香死个人儿了
Friends, this is impressive, so aromatic!
# 漂亮 好
Great! Okay!
# 嚯 皮酥 你知道还一大最大特点是什么啊
Wow! Such a crispy skin, do you know its best feature?
# 汁水锁得好
The juice is locked inside
# 我刚一咬 你看 看见没有
As soon as I bit into it, can you see that?!
# 汁水锁得好
The chicken wings are extremely juicy
# 够味儿 外焦里嫩
Rich in flavour, crispy outside and tender inside
# 三叔推荐 再见
Recommended by San Shu. Goodbye!
# 三叔认可了 没毛病了
Approved by San Shu, wonderful!
# import ending.sbv 0:04:33.940 请原样保留此行